bigassfans.com 2019-05-05

# Privacy Policy | Big Ass Fans

_Last Updated March 27, 2019_

## Recent Updates

Consolidated several internal documents and included the details here to provide more details on how Big Ass Fans considers customer privacy important.

  * Added section titled “Information we collect and how we use it”; 
    * Incorporated Web Site Cookie content from previous version;
    * Added details about SenseME data collected.
  * Added section titled “Information we share”
  * Added section titled “Information we transfer”
  * Added section titled “Links to Other Sites”
  * Added section titled “Children’s Privacy”
  * Added section “How we protect personal information”
  * Added section “Updates to our Privacy Policy”; contains language from prior version
  * Added section “How to contact us”
  * Added section “Notice to California Residents”

## Information we collect and how we use it

Curious about what we do with your data? Well, you’ve come to the right place! When you use any of our websites, our SenseME application or our kickass SenseME products, we may collect information to improve our products and services (progress is kind of our thing), how we market, or to process the data related to energy efficiency and thermal comfort. 

The data collected is gathered using some pretty cool technology, including tools like Google Analytics and reporting from our apps/devices in communication with our cloud servers, aptly dubbed the Big Ass Cloud. Information about your web browser, operating system, pages visited, and more are also gathered through Google Analytics and similar tools. 

If it strikes your fancy, you may choose to provide personal information (such as your name, address, telephone number and email address) on this web site or to Big Ass Fans via other methods as described below. We also tell you how we may use the information (it’s not to stalk you if that’s what you’re worried about). If you use our Haiku Home SenseME products, we’ll collect and store data from your connected fans and/or devices in accordance with this data privacy policy.

Here are some of the ways you may provide the information and the types of information you may submit. Kudos to you for giving a damn!

### Product Registration

When you purchase a product from Big Ass Fans or register through the SenseME application, we may request a variety of information to allow us to provide better service. And better service means a happier YOU. This information can include your name, address, phone number, email address, product’s model number, serial number and purchase date.

### Data from SenseME Products

The data collected is gathered from our apps/devices in communication with our cloud servers, the Big Ass Cloud. This data is used to improve future products and develop more super awesome features or services for our customers.

Our apps and devices collect information such as:

  * Room Temperature
  * The state of the device (examples: on/off, speed)
  * The device’s IP address
  * Occupancy in order to help control energy usage and thermal comfort
  * The device uptime, firmware version, and technical information about the app and device
  * Account information including the data you share during the sign-up process

### Sales, Service and Promotional Activity

If you schedule a service call or delivery, make a consumer inquiry, purchase parts, participate in our promotional activities (such as rebates or contests) or email us through the “Contact Us” link on this site, we ask you for information such as your name and email address so we can respond to your questions and comments. You may choose to provide additional information as well. So click, comment and ask away! Unsurprisingly, we love talking about our products. 

### Questionnaires and Surveys

We occasionally may ask visitors to our web site and consumers to complete online surveys and opinion polls about their activities, attitudes and interests. You’re a donkey person? Hell yes! These surveys help us serve you better and improve the usefulness of our site. In conducting these surveys we may ask you for your name and email address. But no worries; we do not keep any personal information about you in connection with your participation in a Big Ass Fans survey unless you specifically agree to provide that information.

### Information from Third-Party Sources

We may receive information about you from publicly and commercially available sources (as permitted by law), which we may combine with other information we receive from or about you. We also may receive information about you from third-party social networking services when you choose to connect with those services. Yay for interconnectedness! 

### Online Services and Web Browser Tools

Big Ass Fans uses a number of online services to enhance web browsers’ experiences while using the websites and to help plan future website services and marketing offers. We believe in giving power to the people. You should know who these services are so you can choose to opt out of them if you wish.

### Google Analytics

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. This data may include demographic and personal interests they glean from your internet behavior.

  * For the opt-out: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.
  * Personal Data collected: [Cookie and Usage Data](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/types/).
  * Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

### Remarketing through Google Analytics for Display Advertisings

Google Analytics for Display Advertising is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the tracking activity performed by Google Analytics and its Cookies with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.

  * For the opt-out: <https://adssettings.google.com/>.
  * Personal Data collected: [Cookie and Usage Data](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/types/).
  * Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

### AdWords Remarketing

AdWords Remarketing is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the activity of this Application with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.

  * For the opt-out: <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated?hl=en>.
  * Personal Data collected: [Cookie and Usage Data](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/types/).
  * Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

### We use other systems to collect and manage information on our web visitors. This is a list of the tools with links to their data management policies:

  * Salesforce Marketing Cloud: <https://www.salesforce.com/products/marketing-cloud/sfmc/marketing-cloud-anti-spam-policy/>
  * Pardot: <http://www.pardot.com/company/legal/permission-based-marketing-policy/>.
  * Facebook: <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>.
  * Instagram: <https://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/>.
  * Twitter: <https://twitter.com/privacy>.
  * LinkedIn: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>.

### Use of Personal Information

We may use the personal information collected about you for the following purposes:

  * To provide, administer and communicate with you about products, services, events, surveys and promotions (including by sending you marketing communications);
  * To contact you in the event of a service notification for your registered product or to provide other notices concerning the safety of your appliance regardless of your stated privacy preferences.
  * To process, evaluate and respond to your requests, inquiries and applications;
  * To confirm and process your order, provide you with updates regarding your order, process returns and contact you concerning your order;
  * To create, administer and communicate with you about your account (including any purchases and payments);
  * To verify your identity to ensure security for the other purposes listed here;
  * To evaluate your interest in employment and contact you regarding possible employment;
  * To operate, evaluate and improve our business (including developing new products and services; managing our communications; performing market research; determining and managing the effectiveness of our advertising and marketing; analyzing our products, services and websites; administering our websites; and performing accounting, auditing, billing, reconciliation and collection activities);
  * To protect against and prevent fraud, unauthorized transactions, claims and other liabilities, and manage risk exposure and quality;

We also may use personal information for other additional purposes, which we identify at the time of collection. You may choose not to provide us (we can appreciate a little mystery) with certain types of information, but doing so may affect your ability to use some services.

## Information We Share

We share data inside Big Ass Fans with tools and people who are focused on improving the benefits of our products and services and to learn how to better market and sell. Like how we do things around here? Data from previous customers has helped mold us in to who we are today! The tools used to analyze the data are often developed or hosted by third parties through secure browsing sessions and/or encrypted data. 

Your data is super duper safe with us. We limit data shared with any third party even if you connect to them through our apps. For example, if you sign up to connect your Haiku SenseME fan with a smart thermostat like Nest or ecobee, then you can rest assured we do not share any data with the thermostat company. We do access your thermostat’s data to provide better thermal comfort and increased energy efficiency. This information is transmitted through secure connections. If you connect Amazon’s Echo with our awesome Haiku SenseMe fans or lights, we share the name you gave the fan with Echo so Alexa knows what you want when you say “Alexa – turn on the fan in **Bobby’s Room**.”

If you choose to have your products installed by Big Ass Fans or one of our trusted installers, we’ll keep things on lockdown by **not** sharing information about the products you purchased and any specific installation requirements. 

In the event Big Ass Fans receives a valid legal request, we may be required to share your information with authorities who have jurisdiction to make such requests. 

## Information We Transfer

We’re international, baby, so we may transfer the personal information we collect on this site to other countries where we do business, but we will do so only for the purposes described above. When we transfer your information to other countries, we will protect that information as described here unless otherwise required by applicable laws.

If you choose to provide information to us and are located outside the United States of America, please be advised that Big Ass Fans dba Haiku Home will transfer your personal information to the United States of America and process it there. By submitting your personal information, you consent to this Privacy Policy and consent to such transfer. By using this site or otherwise providing Big Ass Fans with your personal information, you warrant that you have the right to transfer such information outside your country and into the United States of America.

## Links to Other Sites

To keep things running ultra-smooth we provide links to other web sites for your convenience and information. These sites may have their own privacy statements in place, which we recommend you review if you visit any linked web sites. We are not responsible for the content of linked sites or any use of the sites.

## Children's Privacy

We have fans of all ages, but this web site is not directed to children under the age of thirteen and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen on Big Ass Fans web sites. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a visitor under the age of thirteen on a Big Ass Fans web site, we will delete the information from our records

## How We Protect Personal Information

We take pride in taking good care of our customers. That’s why we maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against unauthorized disclosure, use, alteration or destruction of the personal information you provide on this web site. We use secure socket layer (SSL) technology and other technologies to help keep the personal information you provide on this site secure.

## Updates to our Privacy Policy

We may update this list from time to time without any notice to the public, so feel free to check back every now and then! Your continued use of our services constitutes acceptance of this policy. 

## How to Contact Us

If you have questions about this privacy policy or wish to have your information removed from our storage locations, please contact us ([info@bigassfans.com](mailto:info@bigassfans.com)). Remember, there’s no such thing as a bad question!

Please note that Big Ass Fans reserves the right to contact you in the event of a safety or quality-related issue with your registered appliance regardless of your stated privacy preferences.

## Notice to California Residents

If you are a resident of the State of California, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your personal information by Big Ass Fans to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [info@bigassfans.com](mailto:info@bigassfans.com) with “California Privacy Information Request” on the subject line and in the body of your message. We will provide the requested information to you at your e-mail address in response.
